# 酥脆
Crispy.
# 鲍鱼茄盒
Abalone Eggplant Box.
# 这个 菜
This dish,
# 过春节可以在家里做一个
You can make one at home during the Spring Festival.
# 茄盒 像鲍鱼一样
The eggplant box, looks like abalone.
# 茄子
Eggplant,
# 要选用长茄子
We should choose those long eggplants,
# 一头大一头小更好
which is better if its head and tail have different sizes.
# 它横切面很像这形状
Its cross section looks like the shape (of abalone),
# 近似（鲍鱼）
likes (abalone)
# 以往的茄盒呢
Previously, the eggplant box
# 是切夹刀片
is sliced like a clip.
# 加上肉馅之后
after layering the mincemeat,
# 一边薄一边厚
it has a different thickness on two sides,
# 不大像鲍鱼
which doesn't look like abalone.
# 只有切成片
Only with slicing into pieces,
# 它最后才能更像一些
it can look like (abalone) when finished.
# 一定要注意茄子的粗细
Be sure to pay attention to the size of the eggplant,
# 要大片跟小片
(the eggplant box) should be made of one larger eggplant slice and another smaller one.
# 配合的比较均匀一点
by which they can match more evenly.
# 两个摞一块儿
Slacking two pieces together,
# 一会儿是这个样子
it will look like this later.
# 这不错
Not bad.
# 茄子切完我们就放旁边了
We set it aside after finishing cutting,
# 然后可以放点淀粉给它拌上
then we can mix them with some starch
# 搁玉米淀粉
Adding some corn starch,
# 一会儿粘肉馅的时候容易粘连
to make it easier to stick with ground meat later.
# 而且把淀粉放上之后
Besides, after we adding the starch,
# 它还可以短时间的
Within a short period of time,
# 隔离一下它的氧化
starch can prevent it from oxidation.
# 对 它不容易变色
Right, not easy to change color.
# 茄盒中间得加馅
The mince should be layered to the middle of the eggplant box.
# 这是肥瘦的猪肉馅
This is fat and lean ground pork meat.
# 您放鸡肉馅 鱼肉馅
You can replace it with chicken, fish,
# 虾肉馅 鸭肉馅都可以
shrimp, or duck, all of those are fine.
# 馅您随便选
whatever meat like.
# 放点盐 胡椒粉 盐
Add some salt, white peper poweder,
# 咱们再放点鲜味酱油
some umami soy sauce,
# 加点葱姜水
add some green union and ginger water,
# 放点香油增加香气
some sesame oil to increase the flavor,
# 还有去腥味的作用
which can remove the gamey taste as well.
# 你看这馅很润 拌的很润
Looks, this mince is very moist,
# 很简单
So easy,
# 朝着一个方向打
stirring in one direction,
# 人家网友说了
Our online friends said,
# 二伯看隋坡的时候
when Er Bai looks at Bo Sui,
# 充着满满的爱
his eyes are full of love.
# 满满的爱
Full of love.
# 特别是二伯胡噜我脑袋的时候
Especially when Er Bai stroke my head,
# 我已经感受到了 是吧
I already felt it.
# 我都没胡噜过你
Even I never stroked you before.
# 好
OK
# 肉馅不加盐搅拌它不起粘度
The mince will not be sticky if we don't add some salt.
# 然后找一片小的
Then we find another small eggplant slice,
# 给它盖上
cover it.
# 这就已经出50%到60%的形状了
So far, it already looks like abalone, almost 50% tp 60%.
# 有点像了 这就像了
Kind of, it looks like (abalone) now.
# 您要是两片大的合一块
If you layered two large eggplant slices together,
# 这就完蛋了 这就不大像了
it's over. It will not look like (abalone).
# 那就是茄盒
That will be the usual eggplant box.
# 然后边上要放淀粉
Then we should add some starch around it,
# 你看它有一定的厚度
See, it is thick.
# 它才像鲍鱼那个边
It looks like the edge of abalone.
# 他这个比一般茄盒香
This one will be more delicious than the usual eggplant box,
# 大爷您知道为什么吗
Do you know why? Da Ye,
# 它这肉多
It has more meat ^_^
# 实惠
Economical.
# 这个糊看得见吧
Look, this batter,
# 这是三两150克脆炸粉
this is 3 liang (150 grams) of crispy frying powder,
# 市场就有卖的
which is selt in the market,
# 大约是120克的水
almost 120 grams of water,
# 一定是糊
It must be batter,
# 稀稠稍微得合适点
the thickness should be right,
# 太厚了 它不下去
It it is too thick, too much of batter will stick in the eggplant;
# 太薄了 是挂不住
If it is too thin, it will not stick with eggplant.
# 得反复的去搅拌
It would help if you stirred it again and again,
# 这个稀稠程度啊 它拉的线
To how thick? Until it can flow like a thread.
# 加点油 里边加点油
Add some oil. We should add some oil to the batter.
# 大约搁多少油呢
About how much?
# 20克纯净的色拉油
20 grams of pure salad oil,
# 起酥脆 使糊挺实的
to make it crispy.
# 一个关键的原料
It is a key ingredient.
# 你看这就行了
Looks, it is ok now.
# 这个鲍鱼茄盒
This abalone eggplant box,
# 要想达到鲍鱼这种形状
to make it look like abalone,
# 就得先煎后炸
we need to pan-fry it first, then deep-fry it with more oil.
# 隋坡一做我就知道了
I know it once Bo Sui do it,
# 因为他这糊啊 有油
Because he adds oil into the batter,
# 有油它起
it will swell if we deep-fry it directly.
# 这一煎就定了形不让它起
However, it won't swell if we pan-fry it and fix the shape of the larger side first.
# 但是后边一炸上边又起来了
But another smaller side will (swell) when deep-fry.
# 可不是呢 你看见没有
That's it. Look.
# 这点秘密都让二伯说明白了
Er Bai clarifies this secret.
# 大鲍鱼您看见没有大爷
A large abalone, do you see? Da Ye.
# 这鲍鱼够个儿
This abalone is large enough.
# 煎时候大约油温
How hot is the oil temperature when we pan-fry it?
# 咱们控制在四成就没有问题
Almost 120C (248F) is fine.
# 主要是为了让它变形
Just to fix the shape,
# 下边定型
fix the shape of the larger side.
# 下边您看定型了
You see, when the shape of the larger side is fixed,
# 就可以捞到油锅里边了
We can move it into the oil-wok (deep-fry it).
# 对 一定要让它倒着炸
Right, must deep-fry it upside down.
# 看底下 他不让它起
Look at the larger side. It won't swell.
# 定了型了底下
The shape of large side is fixed.
# 必须是先煎后炸
It must be pan-fried first, then deep-fry it.
# 两锅要同时用
Two woks should work at the same time,
# 才能达到这种完美的状态
only by this, we can make it perfect.
# 你看这个正好露出黑边来
See, the black border is just exposed.
# 它就很像（鲍鱼）
It looks like abalone.
# 我们还得炸一遍
We need to deep-fry it again.
# 复炸一遍
Second deep-fry again.
# 几成油温 六成了 把馅要炸熟
How hot is the oil temperature? Almost 180C (356F), we should make the mince ready.
# 放纸上
Put it on the kitchen paper,
# 鲍鱼茄盒
Abalone Eddplant Box!
# 这实惠啊这个
So economical, this one.
# 酥脆
Crispy!
# 你看啊 你看 多酥啊
Looks, so crispy.
# 看着
Look.
# 咸味够吗师父
Salty enough? Master?
# 够
Enough.
# 异口同声
Together with one voice.
# 大爷 这真比那茄盒
Da Ye, comparing with the usual eggplant box,
# 那糊好吃
this batter really tastes better,
# 肉香
the meat is delicous.
# 它这烹制方法非常巧妙
Its cooking method is very clever.
# 你看啊 这个是先煎
You see, it was pan-fried first,
# 煎完了它不起
it won't swell after that,
# 它定型了
The shape is fixed,
# 你看到没有
You see that?
# 上边是炸
The smaller side is deep-fried,
# 炸完了 呼起来了
After deep-frying, it swells.
# 一正一反
Different in each side,
# 一煎一炸
Pan-frying one side, deep-frying another side,
# 一煎一炸两种方法
Two methods.